<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<binding:binding id="dsmr"
        xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
        xmlns:binding="http://eclipse.org/smarthome/schemas/binding/v1.0.0"
        xsi:schemaLocation="http://eclipse.org/smarthome/schemas/binding/v1.0.0 http://eclipse.org/smarthome/schemas/binding-1.0.0.xsd">

    <name>DSMR Binding</name>
    <description><![CDATA[ <h3>General information</h3><p>
                This binding makes data from the Dutch Smart Meter available to openHAB2.<br><br>
                There following DSMR-meter versions (V2 - V5) are supported:<ul>
                <li>Electricity (DSMR V2 t/m V5)
                <li>Gas (DSMR V2 t/m V5)
                <li>Heating (DSMR V2 t/m V5)
                <li>Cooloing (DSMR V2 t/m V5)
                <li>Water (DSMR V2 t/m V5)
                <li>Generic (DSMR V3)
                <li>Slave Electricity (DSMR V4 t/m V5)
                </ul>
                Depending on the device model specific values will be available.</p>
                <p>The data from the Smart Meter is available from the P1-port (inverted TTL on a RJ-11 connector).
                    Dedicated cables are available (Search for 'Slimme Meter P1' or 'USB-RJ11').
                </p>
                <h3>Installation & configuration</h3>
                <p>After installing the binding you always need to a 'Dutch Smart Meter' thing manually. This thing needs to be configured
                and has the following parameters:
	                <ul>
		                <li>Serial Port name (mandatory)
		                <li>Serial Port parameters (optional). This can be used in case autodetection port speed fails.
		                <li>Lenient mode (optional). In case of frequent communication loss or CRC-validation problems this mode can be activated to
		                less the binding act less strict.
	                </ul>
                </p>
                <h3>Thing discovery</h3>
                <p>
                The binding will autodiscover a 'Thing' for each available meter. For the newer meters (DSMR V4 and up) the binding can not
                autodiscover the type of each meter (it can not distuinguish a water meter from a gas meter and not a cooling meter from a heating meter).<br>
                This information is not needed for the binding to work so therefor you only have to clarify this in labels and descriptions of Things and Items. 
                </p>
                <h3>Meter (re-)placement</h3>
                There following scenario's are identified during usage of the binding:
                - Initial placement of a DSMR-meter while binding is already running. No special action is needed only set up the correct serial port.
                - Initial placement of additional meters (gas, water, etc.) to the already installed DSMR-meer. No special action is needed. The new meters will be autodetected.
                - Replacement of additional meters (gas, water, etc.). The new meter will be autodetected. You have to remove the old Thing manually.
                - Replacement of DSMR-meter (with or without additional meters). <b>Important.</b> You have to remove all DSMR-related Things to ensure correct working.
                - Removal of DSMR-meter and/or additional meters. Remove the corresponding Things. 
                 ]]></description>
    <author>Marcel Volaart</author>
</binding:binding>
